# **Dobromir Marinov**

Cambridge, United Kingdom

(+44) 7599-943662

mr.d.marinov@gmail.com

https://dmarinov.com/

## Personal Profile

I am a software engineer with more than 4 years of professional experience. As part of my apprenticeship degree at the University of Essex, I achieved the highest degree mark in the computer science and electronic engineering department and successfully completed both a research-based and an applied machine learning project.

## **Employment**

#### Swim.Ai

Software Developer

Cambridge, United Kingdom

September 2019 - Present

- Developing a distributed software platform for edge computing and real-time applications.
- Building commercial products based on the core system.
- Rust, Java, Python, JavaScript.

#### **MSX** International

Software Developer (Machine Learning)

- Development of machine learning models for predictive analytics in the automotive industry.
- Building and deployment of microservices using cloud platforms.
- Python, R, AWS, Docker, Redshift, LATEX.

# Colchester, United Kingdom

June 2018 - September 2019

#### **MSX** International

Software Developer

- Developing web applications for the automotive industry.
- Java, Oracle, Freemarker, Liferay, Hibernate, Gradle, Selenium.

### Colchester, United Kingdom

November 2016 - June 2018

#### StangaOne1

Web Development Intern

- Developing commercial websites for business clients.
- PHP, MySQL, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Laravel, jQuery.

Plovdiv, Bulgaria

July 2016 - September 2016

## Education

### University of Essex

BSc Digital and Technology Solutions (Software Engineer)

Colchester, United Kingdom October 2016 – September 2019

#### Grade:

First-class honours degree with an award for highest degree mark in the computer science and electronic engineering department.

## University-based Capstone Project:

Developing algorithm for automatic hyperparameter optimisation and neural architecture search.

## Work-based Capstone Project:

Creating a machine learning system for prioritisation of customer calls in a call centre.

#### Relevant Modules:

- Software engineering.
- Data structures and algorithms.
- Evolutionary computation and genetic programming.
- Advanced programming.

## Big Data and Analytics Summer School

Delegate

• Learning under different training and testing distributions.

- $\bullet$  Visual recognition and tracking in large image and video datasets.
- Introduction to the modelling and analysis of complex systems.
- Artificial intelligence and neural networks in analytics.

## **High School of Mathematics**

Secondary education

- Program with extensive study of mathematics, english and IT.
- Graduated with excellence: 5.93 out of 6.

Colchester, United Kingdom

July 2018 - August 2018

Plovdiv, Bulgaria September 2011 – June 2016

## Awards

#### Computer Science and Electronic Engineering Prize

University of Essex

 Awarded to the final year student who achieves the highest degree mark. Colchester, United Kingdom July 2019

mark.

#### The Degree Apprenticeship Prize

University of Essex

• Awarded to the second-year apprenticeship degree student with the best overall mark.

Colchester, United Kingdom

September 2018

#### K.F. Bowden Memorial Prize

Colchester, United Kingdom

University of Essex

September 2017

• Awarded to the top 4 first-year students, in CSEE, with the best overall mark.

#### Award of Excellence

Plovdiv, Bulgaria

June 2016

**High School of Mathematics** 

• Awarded for overall performance above 5.80 out of 6.

## Certificates

#### Tech Industry Gold Certificate of Recognition

London, United Kingdom

June 2019

Tech Partnership Degrees

• Nominated by the University of Essex for outstanding academic achievements and awarded by the Tech Partnership Degrees.

## General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)

Colchester, United Kingdom

April 2019

• Certificate for completing a mandatory course in GDPR.

## **Information Security**

Colchester, United Kingdom

**MSX** International

**MSX** International

April 2019

• Certificate for completing a mandatory course in information security.

#### StangaOne1 Academy

Plovdiv, Bulgaria

StangaOne1

January 2016 - May 2016

- Certificate for successfully completing a web development course.
- PHP 5, MySQL, Git, JavaScript, jQuery, AJAX, HTML 5, CSS 3.

## **Publications**

D. Marinov and D. Karapetyan, "Hyperparameter Optimisation with Early Termination of Poor Performers," Computer Science and Electronic Engineering Conference 2019, September 2019.